

Mohd Salman Isha

DevOps Engineer

My Contact

- 🗹 salman.isha@hotmail.com
- +44 7599 664271
- 31 Kimberley Avenue, London, F63BF
- in linkedin.com/in/salmanisha/

Expertise

- AWS(EC2,S3,ELB,Route53,SQS)
- IIS, Apache Tomcat, Wildfly
- MySql, MSSql, MongoDB, Postgres
- HaProxy
- Cacti, Nagios, Zabbix
- Kubernetes
- Ansible
- Jenkins
- ELK Stack
- Redis

Education Background

- University of Wolverhampton
 MSc in Cyber Security with Professional Practice
 Completing in 2022
- Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology

BSc in Computer Science and Engineering Completed in 2011

Solution9 Limited Executive, Senior Executive IT | 2011 - 2015

Key responsibilities:

- Linux, and Windows systems administration. Manage Xen Servers.
- Check network issues and communicate with co-location.
- Monitor the ticket system for work to be performed.
- Maintain IP address records, network management, installation of software, performing backups, configuration management and general system maintenance.
- Provide client support for VoIP Software.

About Me

With ten years of experience, I am a dedicated and passionate DevOps engineer. I had practical experience managing cloud infrastructure and efficiently handling setup and deployment of infrastructure and services such as virtualization, database administration, load balancing, automation, and so on throughout my job experience. Looking for a challenging opportunity to advance into a leadership role in the IT business.

Professional Experience

Realis Simulation

DevOps Engineer | October, 2022 - November, 2022

Key responsibilities:

- Manage Azure and On-premise systems.
- Upkeep of essential infrastructures (Kubernetes, VMs, Dedicated Servers).
- Automate management of configuration and cloud provisioning.
- Putting in place a central monitoring system and notifying the appropriate teams of any problems.

Tiger IT Bangladesh Limited

DevOps Engineer | 2019 - 2021

Key responsibilities:

- Maintain system infrastructure of biometric residence card of People's Republic of Bangladesh.
- Automate cloud provisioning and configuration management.
- Configure & maintain object storage, Database at on premises datacentre.
- Configure ELK stack for centralized log management.
- Maintain open source application container named wildfly.
- · Set up data streaming cluster using Apache kafka.
- Conduct R&D on various open source tools/application to support development team.

Software People Bangladesh Limited Operations Engineer | 2015 - 2019

Key responsibilities:

- Provide ops support for the application used by renowned brands like Dell, Best buy, Ford.
- Configure & maintain Amazon Web Services.
- Configure & maintain Windows/Linux/Database Servers.
- Security patch update periodically for all (Production, Test, Staging, UAT) environment.
- Responsible for managing AD, ADFS, Mail servers.
- Closely work with developers to deploy latest release/feature into production environment.
- Implement backup strategy of servers, databases, and files & disaster recovery system.
- Configure Go automation tool to automate deployment related work.
- Implement several (PowerShell, Batch, Shell, python) scripting language to automate day to day work.